A Guide to the Mary-Cooke Branch Munford Papers, 1881-1935
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Mary-Cooke Branch Munford Papers, 1881-1935
Library of Virginia
28142
12.6 cubic feet (30 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information unavailable.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mary-Cooke Branch Munford was born in Richmond, Virginia on 15 September 1865. She was educated in Richmond and New York, and married Beverley Bland Munford on 22 November 1893. She co-founded the Richmond Educational Association in 1901; chairman, Co-ordinate College League, 1910-1926; president, Cooperative Educational Association of Virginia, 1910-1925; vice-president, National Consumers' League; member, Board of Visitors, The College of William and Mary and The University of Virginia; first woman member of the Richmond School Board; chairman, Woman's Committee of the Council of National Defense; and member, Virginia Agricultural Council of Safety; member of the Board of the Virginia and Richmond League of Women Voters; member of the Board, National Urban League. She died in Richmond on 3 July 1938.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1881-1938, of Mary-Cooke Branch Munford of Richmond, Virginia, documenting her work in various political, educational, social, economic, and inter-racial endeavors. The bulk of the collection covers the period from 1910-1930, when she was most active.
The CO-ORDINATE COLLEGE LEAGUE series includes correspondence and subject files concerning Munford's and the League's attempts to convince The University of Virginia to admit women by establishing a coordinate college with its own organization, and its own social, residence and instruction halls. The new college would share the library and laboratories of the University, and students would be taught by some of its faculty. The papers include correspondence from educators at the University of Virginia, as well as around the state and nation, business leaders, politicians, and members of the League. The subject files contain accounts, legislative information, including research data, drafts of bills introduced on behalf of the League, and voting records of the members of the General Assembly, resolutions, brochures, flyers, and pamphlets, mailing and membership lists, and information from various educational, labor, alumni, and other groups opposing and supporting the League's efforts. There is also a large amount of clippings from Richmond newspapers, as well as other Virginia newspapers, which document the League's activities.
The EDUCATION series includes information on Munford's activities in the field of education. It includes information from The University of Virginia, including dockets and minutes of the Board of Visitors, the Richmond Education Association, the Richmond Lancastrian School, Southern Industrial Classes, and the Richmond public schools. Also included is information on the status, salaries, and working conditions of teachers. This series also contains a variety of published newsletters, bulletins, annual reports, and other educational publications.
The FOREIGN POLICY AND NATIONAL POLITICS series contains subject files documenting Munford's assistance during World War I, and her interest in world peace. It includes a large amount of material on here work on the Women's Committee of the Council of National Defense during the war, and her help in food conservation and registration drives. There is also information on her activities in the Foreign Policy Association and the Walter Hines Page School of International Relations, as well as peace groups, including the Conference on the Cause and Cure of War. This series also contains material on Munford's involvement in the Democratic Party and the League of Women Voters.
The RACE RELATIONS series includes subject files on Munford's activities with the Commission on Inter-racial Cooperation, Richmond Urban League, National Urban League, Woman's Inter-Racial Committee, National League on Urban Conditions Among Negroes, Committee on Colored Work, and the Commission on Inter-racial Cooperation. There is also correspondence, clippings, and financial information, as well as publications concerning race relations.
The VIRGINIA'S ATTITUDE TOWARD SLAVERY AND SECESSION series concerns this book, written by her husband, Beverley Bland Munford, in 1909. Much of the material concerns Mrs. Munford's work in getting the book re- adopted by the State Board of Education as required text in history courses taught in high schools in Virginia after her husband's death in 1910. The series contains correspondence, briefs and comments, circular letters, and postcards, as well as material on the book's publication, orders, and sales.
The MISCELLANEOUS SUBJECT FILES series contains accounts, bank statements, correspondence, a notebook belonging to Beverley Bland Munford, dated 1881-1885, and information on other groups and activities in which Mrs. Munford was involved. There are also blueprints of alterations to her cottage in Maine by William Lawrence Bottomley, dated 1923, filed in the General Architectural Files, Folder 126. Also included in this series are clippings and publications.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. Co-ordinate College League. II. Education. III. Foreign Policy and National Politics. IV. Race Relations. V. VIRGINIA'S ATTITUDE TOWARD SLAVERY AND SECESSION. VI. Miscellaneous Subject Files.
Contents List
- Series I: Co-ordinate College League
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alderman, Edwin A., 1912-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alderman, Edwin A., 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Alderman, Edwin A., 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alexander, James Selman, 1914-1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Babcock, Kendrick C., 1909-1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Barrett, Mrs. Annie K., 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barton, Mrs. Robert (Gertrude W.), 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bruce, Philip Alexander, 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Buchanan, Mrs. B.F. (Nellie S.), 1914-1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bunch, Frank M., 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - Caldwell, Mrs. M.M. (Willie W.), 1913-1918 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Campbell, Mrs. A.A. (Susie S.), 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Cannon, James E., Jr., 1913-1917 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Carson, William E., 1914-1918 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Chandler, J.A.C., 1913-1919 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Chapman, W.R., 1914-1918 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Colton, Elizabeth Avery, 1913-1916 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Craddock, John W., 1912-1916 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - D (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Davis, Lucy L., 1912-1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Westmoreland, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Devany, Mrs. W.L. (Anna W.), 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Duval, Maria Pendleton, 1913-1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - E (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Early, N.B., Jr., 1913 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ellis, Mrs. C.C. (Laura J.), 1914-1918 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - F (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Farmwille-J.L. Jarman, 1910-1917 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Flippen, Mrs. O.G. (Florence B.), 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Flood, Henry D., 1914-1918 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - G (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gaines, Elizabeth V., 1913-1918 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gannaway, D.M., 1912-1914 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Garnett, Judge Christopher, nd (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Gildersleeve, Virginia C., 1913-1916 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Goodwyn, Mrs. Thompson (Martha L.), 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Gordon, Armistead, 1912-1917 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Green, Kate T., 1913-1916 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - H (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
    - Hagan, Mrs. John L. (Janie Gray), 1915-1918 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Harman, Daniel, 1912-1914 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Hart, Harris, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Holt, Miss Lucy Mason, 1914-1918 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Hunley, W.M., 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Hunton, Eppa, Jr., 1912 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - I (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Israel, Mrs. Frank T. (Cora M.), 1915-1916 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ivy, Elizabeth, 1914-1918 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - J (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Jacob, Cary Franklin, 1916-1920 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, Mrs. J.W. Cantey, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - K (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Kensett, Nannie D., 1916 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Kyle, Mrs. James R. (Alice J.), 1912-1918 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - L (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Legislature-Letters, 1914-1918 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Livers, John L., 1914-1920 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
    - Mann, Emmett Lee, nd (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Maphis, Charles G., 1911-1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Means, Mrs. E.C. (Ruby R.), 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Montague, Mrs. A.P., 1913-1916 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Moore, R. Walton, 1913-1919 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Mc (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - McConnell, John P., 1912-1918 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - N (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Nelson, John Poyntz, 1913-1918 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Norton, Judge J.K.M., 1913-1917 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - O (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - P (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Page, J.M., 1913-1918 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Page, Roswell, 1915-1918 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Pickett, Elizabeth, 1914-1915 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Pitt, Miss Virgie Lee, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Priddy, Mrs. J.H. (Elizabeth Lee), 1914-1917 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Q (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - R (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Ramsey, D. Hiden, 1912-1913 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Riddick, Mrs. S.A. (Virginia Griffin), 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Robertson, Alex F., 1918 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - S (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
    - Scott, Katherine K., 1915-1917 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Smith, E. Virginia, 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Smith, J. Sidney, 1916-1917 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Stone, Ormond, 1912-1918 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Strode, Aubrey E., 1910-1918 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - T (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Thomas, M. Carey, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Thomas, Mary Fitzhugh Randolph, 1914-1916 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Thornton, William M., 1912-1919 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Turpin, Edna, 1916-1918 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - U (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - V (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Venable, Emma C., 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - W (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - White, Mrs. B.B. (Helen Taylor Crews), 1915-1917 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Williams, Miss Frances, 1913-1916 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Williams, Mrs. James H. (Janie), 1916-1918 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Wood, Mrs. Joseph B., 1914-1916 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Y (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2: Subject files
    - Account Book, 1914-1918 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Account Book, 1915-1916 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Alumni-University of Virginia, 1912-1918 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Articles Appearing in University Publications, 1912-1916 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Articles Opposed to the Coordinate College, 1916-1918 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Association of Collegiate Alumnae, 1915-1916 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Bills, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Bills, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - Board of Visitors Public Hearing, 11 December 1913 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Board of Visitors Resolutions, 1913-1918 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Brochures and Flyers, 1912-1918 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Budgets, 1911-1917 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Byrd-The Dinkey-A Poem Dedicated to Hon. R.E. Byrd, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Central Committee-Chairmen and Members- Letters, 1914-1918 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Changes in the Standards of Colleges (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Charlottesville-City Council Resolutions, etc., 1914-1918 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Colleges for Women (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
    - Colleges for Women-Delaware College (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Committee of Twenty Five-Educational Conference of Virginia (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Common School Data (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Contributors (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - The Co-ordinate College at Charlottesville, Draft, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
    - The Co-ordinate College at Charlottesville, Extra Copies of Letters, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Co-ordinate College at Charlottesville, Final Copy, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Co-ordinate College League Budget, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Co-ordinate College League Minutes, 1914-1918 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Co-ordinate College League Publications (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cost Pamphlet Data, 1915-1917 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Department of Public Instruction Publications (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Education-Viscount Bryce on Public Education, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Elementary Teachers' Association, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Enrollment in Colleges, 1911-1918 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes- University of Virginia, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Farmers' Union- Resolutions, etc., 1912-1918 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Federation of Labor- Resolutions, etc., 1912-1916 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Federations of Mothers' Clubs, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Federation of Womens' Clubs- letters, etc., 1910-1916 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Form Letters, 1914-1918 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - High School Teachers, Training of, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - History of the University of Virginia (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Legislature (Voting Records) (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
    - Letters and Manuscripts for Possible Publication (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
    - Lists (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
    - Mailing List (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Membership Lists, First-Third Districts 1914 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Membership Lists, Fourth-Seventh Districts, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Membership Lists, Eighth-Tenth Districts, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Membership Lists, First-Fifth Districts, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Membership Lists, First-Fifth Districts, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Membership Lists, Sixth-Tenth Districts, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Normal Schools (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Opposition Literature (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlet Manuscript (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Per Capita Cost-University of Virginia Data, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Publications of Alumni Opposed (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Resolutions-Not Filed Elsewhere (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - State Teachers' Association (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - State Universities- Statistics, Enrollment, Funds, etc. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - U.D.C. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - University of Virginia- Students, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Education Commission (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - V.P.I. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Vocations for College Women (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Women's Education-History, Data, etc. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Women's Part in the Education of the South" (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 3: Clippings
    - Clippings from Richmond Dailies, 1910-1913 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Clippings from Richmond Dailies, 1914-1915 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Clippings from The Evening Journal and The Richmond Virginian, 1916-1918 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Clippings from The News Leader and The Times-Dispatch, 1916-1918 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - State Papers Other Than Richmond Dailies, 1910-1915 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Clippings from Virginia Papers Other Than Richmond Dailies and Out of State Papers, 1914-1917 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Clippings from Newspapers Other Than Richmond Dailies, 1917-1918 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Clippings About Coeducation (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Clippings of General Information (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Clippings of General Information, Book I, 1912-1918 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Misc. Clippings on Women's Education (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Univeristy of Virginia College Topics-Alumni News, Summer School News, etc., 1913-1918 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Series II: Education
  - Subseries 1: Subject files
    - Alderman, Edwin A., 1926-1930 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Armstrong High School (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Boatwright, F.W., 1926 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Clippings (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Coal for Schools (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Dean of Women- University of Virginia, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Drinking at the University of Virginia- Clippings, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Education in Virginia- Report, 1905 [?] (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Ellett, Jennie, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Floor Plans for Richmond Schools, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Housing Conditions for Women in Southern State Universitites, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Kaylor, Alice R., 1931 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Layman Bill, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - List of Accredited Four-Year High Schools, 1925-1926 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Married Teachers, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Nursery Schools, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Report on the Status of Opportunities for Women in Southern State Univerisities, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Richmond Education Association, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Richmond Lancastrian School (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Richmond League of Teachers, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Richmond Public Schools, 1921-1931 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Salaries-Teachers, 1925-1927 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Schools-Finance, 1923-1928 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "Shorter Hour Experiment" Report, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Southern Industrial Classes, 1904-1906 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Statistical Survey of Expenditures for Higher Education in Virginia, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Technical High School, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - University of Virginia, 1926-1931 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - University of Virginia Board of Visitors (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
    - University of Virginia Board of Visiters-Dockets, 1925-1927 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - University of Virginia Board of Visitors-Dockets, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - University of Virginia Board of Visiters- Dockets, 1930-1936 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - University of Virginia Board of Visitors- Minutes, 1926-1927 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - University of Virginia Board of Visitors- Minutes, 1928-1930 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - University of Virginia Extension Division, 1926-1930 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Social Science Association, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - William & Mary (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 2: Publications
    - University of Virginia Alumni News, 1916-1921 (Box 15)
    - Community League News, January - December 1924 (Box 15)
    - State Board of Education Bulletins and Annual Reports, 1918-1925 (Box 15)
    - State Superintendent of Public Instruction Reports, 1914-1916 (Box 15)
    - Other Miscellaneous Publications (Box 15)
- Series III: Foreign Policy and National Politics
  - Subseries 1: Subject Files
    - Accounts- Foreign Policy Association (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - China (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
    - Clippings (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Committee on Safeguarding of Moral and Spiritual Forces, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Conference on the Cause and Cure of War (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
    - Council of National Defense- Committee on Women's Defense Work, 1917 (Vol. 1) (Box 16, Folder 8-10)
    - Council of National Defense- Women's Committee, 1917-1918 (Box 16, Folder 11-16)
    - Council of National Defense- Women's Committee- Clippings (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Democratic Party, League of Women Voters, Women's Party, "Women Citizen" (B-W) (Box 17, Folder 2-14)
    - Fascists (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Food Conservation Committee, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Food Registration (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1926-1927 (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
    - Foreign Policy Association- News Bulletin, 1925-1927 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Kahn, Otto H., 1926 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - League of Nations (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - League of Women Voters (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
    - Mexico- Clippings, 1926 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - National Council for Prevention of War (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Walter Hines Page School of International Relations (Box 18, Folder 7-11)
    - Virginia Agricultural Council of Safety, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - War Programs, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - War Library, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Women's Organizations, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Series 2: Publications
    - Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America-Information Service, 1927-1930 (Box 19)
    - Foreign Policy Association- Information Service, 1927-1928 (Box 19)
    - Other Miscellaneous Foreign Policy Publications (Box 19)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace- International Conciliation, 1915-1927 (Box 20)
    - Conference on the Cause and Cure of War- Reports, 1925-1926 (Box 20)
    - League of Nations News, 1925-1927 (Box 20)
    - Foreign Policy Association Reports, 1924-1927 (Box 21)
    - Publications on Relations with China, 1925-1926 (Box 21)
- Series IV: Race Relations
  - Subseries 1: Subject Files
    - Bowie, Walter Russell (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Church Women's Committee on Race Relations (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1922-1930 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Commission on Inter-Racial Cooperation, 1921-1929 (Box 22, Folder 4-11)
    - Commission on Inter-Racial Cooperation- Women's Committee, 1921-1929 (Box 22, Folder 12-13)
    - Commission on Negro Churches and Race Relations (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Commission on the Church and Race Relations (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - F (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Fisk University- Treasurer's Report and Budget Schedule, 1927-1928 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - H (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - K (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - L (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - M (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Maternity Home Situation, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - N (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - National Urban League, 1919-1930 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Negro (F-W) (Box 23, Folder 8-16)
    - P (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - R (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Race Relations (Box 23, Folder 19-20)
    - Richmond Urban League, 1926-1931 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - S (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Schools- Negro, 1920-1922 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - V (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - W (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Y (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Zoning (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 2: Publications
    - Publications of the Commission on Inter-Racial Cooperation (Box 24)
    - Opportunity- A Journal of Negro Life, 1923-1927 (Box 24)
    - Other Miscellaneous Publications (Box 24)
- Series V: Virginia's Attitude Toward Slavery and Secession
  - Subseries 1: Subject Files
    - Adoption by State Board of Education- Correspondence, 1911-1926 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
    - Adoption by State Board of Educaiton- Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Briefs and Comments (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Circular Letters- Depositories, Superintendents, etc., 1923-1926 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Circulars, Postcards, etc., 1911-1922 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Comments- Teachers, Citizens, Superintendents, 1914-1923 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Course of Study (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
    - G (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Hart, Harris, 1921-1926 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - High Schools (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Hunter & Company, Inc. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Jenkins (Book Manufacturer) (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - List of Teachers, Superintendents, etc. (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Longmans, Green & Co. (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Members-State Board of Education- Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Macmillan Company (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Orders (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - P (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Printing Companies (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Questionnaires (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Questions and Answers (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Reviews (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Sales (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - State Board of Educaiton (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - State Teachers' Association (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Suggestions (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Textbook Circular Letters (Box 26, Folder 13)